Verse 16.
The Bible says, "Thus saith the Lord,
stand in the ways and see,
and ask for the old
paths,
where the good
way is,
and walk in it.
Then,
you'll find rest for your souls.
But they said,
"We will not walk
in it."
Father, thank you for the reading of
your word. Bless it to our heart this
morning.
Let the church be edified.
We magnify you. We exalt you. Let heaven
rejoice. In Jesus' name I pray. Somebody
say amen.
Amen. You may be seated in the presence
of the Lord.
I'm going to be collecting the
Some people took envelopes from me last
Sunday.
Uh
In fact, I can't even do it right now.
If you have the envelope you collected
for the mixer, we're raising money for
the mixer,
uh please uh
bring it to me and I'll be happy to
receive it before the ministry of God's
word.
Almost forgot it. It's so important.
If you picked an envelope from me about
the mixer last Sunday, God bless you.
Clap for them as they come.
God bless you. God bless you for
honoring your pledges.
God bless you. God bless you. God bless
you.
God bless you. God bless you.
God bless you. Amen. God bless you.
Please put your hands together for them.
There are people who paid by M-Pesa, I
understand.
If you paid by M-Pesa, lift up your
hand.
For the mixer.
God bless you, professor.
God bless you. God bless you. God bless
you. Put your hands together for all
these people.
Amen.
You should have come to say hello to me,
also.
Amen.
But, we appreciate your support
and
propagation of the ministry.
Uh
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen, today
we celebrate Old Sunday.
Uh but, this is not just merely uh
dressing in vintage clothes and uh
singing old hymns.
Uh today is also a reminder that the old
paths of God
still carry power.
Uh
the God who moved in past generations
has not changed.
If it's the scripture that I remember
myself as I was growing up that we used
to quote
every time was Jesus Christ the same
yesterday,
today and forever.
Ladies and gentlemen, brothers and
sisters,
church history is filled with towering
figures who shaped Christianity
and Christian theology.
They shaped global mission,
led massive cultural awakenings.
And some of the biggest names, if I
would mention them this morning, you'd
be able to remember them.
Names like Martin Luther,
the Protestant Reformists,
John Wesley,
the Methodist leader,
Charles Spurgeon,
the prince of preachers,
>> [snorts]
>> Billy Graham,
the 20th century evangelist,
Jonathan Edwards,
1703 to 1758,
key figure in the First Great Awakening
and a towering intellectual
of the American church history,
George Whitefield,
1714 to 1770,
an itinerant English evangelist whose
booming voice and open-air preaching
ignited revivals
across both Great Britain and the
American colonies.
Names continue
of all the
mightily used anointed preachers of God.
I can mention William Carey, an English
missionary to India, widely known as the
father of modern missions.
I can mention here with us Charles
Haddon Spurgeon, 1834 to 1892,
the great preacher
preaching the Metropolitan Tabernacle in
London.
Kathryn Kuhlman,
mightily anointed woman that is
anointing that rested upon her
didn't even have to speak, but people
around would just cry out in repentance.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen, all the paths produced men of
prayer,
holy living,
reverence for God, powerful worship,
strong families,
and revival fire.
We live in a generation that wants
shortcuts, convenience,
and entertainment.
But God is calling his people back to
the ancient paths.
I'm so delighted that somebody somewhere
thought we can have an old Sunday.
Much credit goes to them for this great
Sunday that we call old Sunday that
reminds us of the old paths.
For the few minutes that we have, allow
me to remind you
that all the paths
were old paths of prayer.
Luke chapter 5 and verse 16,
scripture says, "And he withdrew himself
into the wilderness and prayed."
The old believers understood the power
of prayer.
Before technology and before
microphones,
before social media,
before internet,
believers shook nations through prayer.
Old school Christianity believed prayer
changes things.
Older school
paths believed that prayer
opened doors.
Prayer
broke yolks.
>> [snorts]
>> Old paths believed that prayer
sustained revival.
Yes, ladies and gentlemen, brothers and
sisters, there was a man known as John
Knox.
John Knox's prayer life shook the whole
of England.
That Mary, Queen of Scots, famously
declared
she feared his prayers more than all the
armies of Europe.
I'm telling you this morning
that the old path
one of the marks of the old path was the
power of prayer.
Prayer meetings were meetings full of
fire and anointing.
And miracles happened. They didn't need
a pastor for miracles to happen because
they believed in the power of prayer.
They would pray before they called a
doctor.
policeman.
Yes, old paths were paths
of prayer.
Can I remind you that a powerless
church, a prayerless church is a
powerless church, and a powerless church
is often a prayerless church.
And so, I'm here to remind you that the
olden days were days
that were days of prayer.
That's what really marked the old olden
days apart from uh
the fashion that we enjoy this morning.
But old paths were also paths of
holiness.
1 Peter chapter 1 and verse 16, the
scripture says that you be holy for I am
holy. In the olden days, believers
feared God.
Holiness was not legalism.
Holiness was love and reverence for God.
People guarded their speech.
People guarded what they said.
People guarded their their conversation.
They were people who walked
>> [snorts]
>> in holiness.
Their conduct
was marked by holiness. Their
relationships were marked by holiness.
Their appearance
was marked by holiness. It was not
legalism for them to dress decently.
It was not legalism for them not to
expose their flesh.
IT WAS HOLINESS THAT GUIDED THE OLD
CHURCH AND THAT GOING TO CHURCH WAS NOT
A FASHION SHOW TO EXPOSE FLESH.
BUT IT WAS IMBIBED AND guarded
by people who revered
the holy one of Israel. YES, THE OLD
PATH WAS marked by holiness. I'm
surprised nowadays that people go to
church the way they feel like. But in
the olden days, oh yes, fashion was
guarding yourself in decency and respect
for the holy God who reigns forevermore.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen, the old path
was marked by holiness.
But God still
honors
>> [snorts]
>> holiness.
Yes, you can do all fashion you want.
God still declares I'm the holy one.
Can somebody say amen?
Brothers and sisters, today many want
the power of God without the purity of
God. But in the old times, they feared
God and they walked in reverence and
in holiness.
The modern church
must not replace the scripture
with modern motivation.
Holiness comes first.
Yes.
Also, one of the marks of the old olden
days really is the respect and the honor
for the word of God.
The Bible says in Psalm 119 and verse
11, "Thy word have I hidden in my heart
that I might not sin against thee."
Still remember the song we used to sing,
"Thy word is a lamp unto my feet and a
light unto my path." Yes, ladies and
gentlemen, in the olden days, the old
church, people carried their scriptures
with them. In the old days, people
carried Bibles. The old Gideon Bible was
a mark of being a Christian. Quoting
scripture was the norm of the day.
Telling people, "It is written." was the
word that emanated from their mouths.
They worshipped God in holiness. They
revered the word of God. They had the
authenticity
of the word of God. It was in the olden
days. I remember very clearly that my
father himself used to carry a Bible in
the inner pocket of his suit. Because
whenever he would meet you, he would
tell you what the word has to say.
Today, we know more about TikTok THAN WE
KNOW ABOUT the word of God. It's a high
TIME THAT THE CHURCH GOES BACK, NOT JUST
TO OLD FASHIONS, BUT TO THE OLD WAYS OF
revering the word of God.
Yes, I need to tell somebody this
morning there's still power in the word.
I'm going to remind you, HEAVEN AND
EARTH WILL PASS AWAY, BUT THE WORD OF
GOD WILL NEVER PASS AWAY. THAT IS THE
OLD CHURCH THAT YOU COME FROM. THAT'S
THE OLD CHURCH YOUR FATHER WENT TO.
THAT'S THE OLD CHURCH YOUR MOTHER WENT
TO. THAT'S THE OLD CHURCH THAT YOUR
GRANDFATHER BELONGED TO. THAT THEY
BELIEVED IN THE WORD OF GOD. COME ON,
SOMEBODY. IT'S A HIGH TIME THAT THE
CHURCH GOES BACK TO THE WORD. I HEAR
PEOPLE preaching today and I wonder
whether they are cartoons or they are
preachers BECAUSE THEY ARE EMPTY OF THE
WORD OF GOD. THEY ARE EMPTY WHEN IT
COMES TO THE WORD OF GOD. THEY ARE EMPTY
WITH THEOLOGY. TODAY, THE MORE YOU MAKE
PEOPLE TO LAUGH IS THE MORE YOUR CHURCH
IS FULL. BUT IN THE OLDEN DAYS, IT WAS
THE WORD THAT RULED THE DAY. IT IS THE
WORD THAT PREACHERS PREACHED. YOU ARE
NOT KNOWN AS A CARTOON. YOU ARE KNOWN
[screaming]
BECAUSE YOU ARE FULL OF THE WORD OF GOD.
THE OLDEN days
were days of the word.
I AM SHOCKED, HONESTLY.
AND I'M APPALLED WHEN I LISTEN TO SOME
PREACHERS PREACH.
THEY HAVE EVEN TITLES OF ARCHBISHOP.
BUT YOU HARDLY EVEN HEAR THEM EXPOUND
THE WORD OF GOD.
YOU WONDER WHETHER YOU CAME TO HEAR
STORIES
OF HOW YOU SHOULD NOT WEAR, I DON'T
KNOW, THEN THE word This is This is This
one is very famous, by the way. This one
of women not wearing, you know, kangas
and what have you. Please, I I
JUST JUST JUST modify it a bit and just
use your head. Make it a bit more than
kidogo because that one HAS BEEN
OVERUSED. BUT YOU SEE, WHEN YOU'RE
PREACHING THE WORD OF GOD, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY. WHEN YOU'RE PREACHING THE
WORD OF GOD, ALL THAT YOU NEED IS IN THE
WORD. ALL THAT YOU NEED IS JUST HIDDEN
IN THE WORD OF GOD.
Don't have to MANUFACTURE STUFF.
THE CHURCH [screaming]
THE OLDEN CHURCH
WAS A CHURCH
OF THE WORD.
THE CHURCH
WAS BUILT ON THE FOUNDATION OF THE WORD.
THE WORD WAS THE COMPASS.
THE WORD [screaming] WAS THE WEAPON.
AND THE WORD
WAS the light.
Well, another mark
of the old and church
is that the old church had
the path that produced strong faith.
Jesus Christ is same yesterday, today,
and forever. Hebrews 13 and 8.
The old generation trusted God for
everything.
Everything.
They believed God for healing when
somebody was sick.
All they prayed for healing.
They prayed FOR PROVISION.
FOR GOD to provide.
They understood that God is a provider.
Hallelujah.
They prayed for protection.
In the highways
and the byways,
they would pray for protection.
All you needed was to visit your
grandmother.
And your grandmother, before you leave
the visitation, they would say, "Let us
pray."
And if you came into the house,
even before you sit down,
some of them will say,
"Let us pray."
Before you can eat, "LET US PRAY."
OH GOD, THAT CHURCH WAS A CHURCH THAT
was full of faith. And that they
believed God for everything. Even in the
hardship times, they did not ABANDON
GOD. THEIR FAITH was not based on
feelings,
BUT THEIR FAITH WAS BASED ON CONVICTION.
GOD IS STILL LOOKING for believers who
will trust him completely.
I am looking forward to the day when the
church will go back. When they will
believe God for everything. You'll
believe God when you wake up in the
morning that you'll go out and come back
safely.
You'll believe God when you go out, GOD
IS GOING TO GUIDE YOU. GOD IS GOING to
protect you. GOD IS GOING TO watch over
you. Hallelujah. AND THAT WHATEVER FIRE
YOU'RE GOING INTO, YOU KNOW THAT GOD is
with you. How I pray that we go back to
the days of Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abednego. That even if you're thrown
into the fire, you know that he is with
you. AND THAT GOD WILL GO WITH YOU. AND
THAT IF HE'S NOT WITH YOU, HE'LL KEEP
YOU OUT OF THE FIRE. GIVE YOUR NEIGHBOR
A HIGH FIVE AND TELL THEM, "LET ME HAVE
FAITH."
COME ON. COME ON. COME ON. COME ON. LET
ME JUST HAVE FAITH. BECAUSE IF I HAVE
FAITH LIKE THAT ONE OF SHADRACH,
MESHACH, AND ABEDNEGO, IF I HAVE FAITH
LIKE THAT ONE OF DANIEL, IF I CAN BE
THROWN INTO THE LION'S DEN, I KNOW THAT
MY GOD IS STILL WITH ME. I MAY NOT SEE
HIM PHYSICALLY, BUT HIS PRESENCE WALKS
WITH ME. I MAY NOT TOUCH HIM PHYSICALLY,
BUT I KNOW HE HAS NOT LEFT ME. AM I
TALKING TO SOMEBODY HERE? I FEEL LIKE
SOMEBODY'S GETTING THE FAITH TO BE
REMINDED THAT GOD IS WITH YOU. TOUCH
YOUR NEIGHBOR, TELL THEM, "GOD IS WITH
YOU." COME ON. COME ON. COME ON. TOUCH
YOUR NEIGHBOR, "GOD IS WITH YOU."
REGARDLESS OF WHAT YOU'RE GOING THROUGH,
regardless of the fire, REGARDLESS OF
THE FIGHTS, GOD IS WITH YOU. HAVE THE
FAITH THAT GOD IS WITH YOU IN YOUR
STRUGGLES, IN YOUR MESSES, IN YOUR
FIGHTS. HAVE THE FAITH THAT GOD IS WITH
YOU. STAND UP AND GIVE SOMEBODY A HIGH
FIVE AND TELL THEM, "GOD [screaming] IS
WITH YOU."
HALLELUJAH.
Be seated. The old church was a church
of faith.
It didn't matter who was fighting
against it. They believed in God. They
were persecuted, they believed in God.
They were killed, they believed in God.
Nero tried to exterminate them, BUT THEY
BELIEVED IN GOD. THEY WERE BURNED TO
LIGHT THE CITIES OF ROME, BUT THEY
BELIEVED IN GOD. RIGHT HERE IN UGANDA,
IDI AMIN TRIED TO KILL THEM, THROW THEM
TO THE NILE, BUT THEY BELIEVED IN GOD.
THEY HAD A FAITH THAT THERE IS A GOD
[screaming] IN HEAVEN. THEY HAD A FAITH
THERE WAS A GOD. HALLELUJAH.
HOW I PRAY THAT THE CHURCH WILL GO BACK
TO GREAT FAITH AND BELIEVE IN A GOD WHO
IS GREATER THAN ANY PROBLEM, BIGGER THAN
ALL YOUR PROBLEMS, BIGGER THAN ALL YOUR
COMPETITION. GOD IS BIGGER.
THE old church believed
and had a faith
in a God
who is able.
Hallelujah.
Glory to God.
That is what old church is all about.
Old church
is not wearing just a good uh
tuxedo.
It's also
going to the old ways
of faith.
Well,
the other thing that marked the old
church
was the path
of revival.
Psalm 85 and verse 6,
Bible says, "Will thou not revive us
again?
That thy people may rejoice in thee."
"WILT THOU NOT REVIVE us
again, that thy people
may rejoice
in thee?"
Old revival meetings
were common.
People going for revival meetings.
Meetings that were marked by repentance,
conviction, salvation,
deliverance,
and deep worship.
I don't know what happened to those
meetings, but I remember I used to go to
them.
They were organized in all the parts of
this country.
Where people would go for camp meetings,
revival meetings.
And they would really sing and worship
God in spirit and in truth.
Alvin Slaughter kept on singing numerous
songs, different songs.
Revive us again.
Hymns like Hallelujah,
Find the glory,
REVIVE
US
AGAIN.
REVIVE US, OH GOD, AGAIN.
YES, the Bible says, "Won't thou revive
us again that thy people
may rejoice
in thee."
People did not rush out of church.
They tarried in God's presence.
The church today needs more programs.
They need more uh mechanical things,
but they need the revival of God.
Which should be the opposite. Throughout
history,
cities like Nineveh in Assyria,
New York, the USA,
Los Angeles, the USA,
experienced massive city-wide repentance
during spiritual awakenings.
This sweeping moral transformation
dramatically reduced crime,
altered the local economy,
and sparked lasting social reforms
in these regions.
Yes,
my brothers and sisters,
the old days were days
of revival and camp meetings where God
moved miraculously
and changed lives in the reverence of
God in these cities.
Well, the other mark that we have
of the old path
honored God's house.
Ecclesiastes chapter 5 and verse 1, Keep
thy foot then thou goest to the house of
God. Keep thy foot
when thou goest into the house of God.
Keep thy foot when thou goest to the
house of God.
The old path honored God's house.
People came prepared.
People respected worship.
People
honored spiritual authority.
valued fellowship.
Church was not treated casually
like it is treated today.
Church was revered.
When reverence returns to the church,
glory
returns.
Yes,
in the olden days, the house of God
was respected. The house of God was
revered.
I hear stories nowadays
of people even stealing in the church,
and I wonder if they have an
understanding of what the house of God
is all about. I hear
a bishop or a minister being killed in
the compound of the church, and I wonder
what happened to the reverence
for the house
of God. I hear that political
insinuation causes a pastor to be
killed, AND I WONDER WHAT HAPPENED?
[screaming]
TO THE FEAR
OF GOD.
YES.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
old school Sunday
is not about going back culturally.
It's about returning
spiritually.
Hallelujah.
The old path
still works
today.
To God be all the glory, and the church
shouts a big
amen. Amen. Give the Lord a big clap
offering.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
the church needs to go back to prayer,
to holiness, to passion, to reverence,
and to revival.
Yes.
Prayer still works.
Holiness still works. The word still
works. Faith still works. Revival still
works.
Jesus still saves.
Let's stand up on our feet.
Hallelujah. Father, in the name of
Jesus, I pray that the fire of the
revival returns to our lives.
I pray, oh God, in the name of Jesus,
that prayer rises again in your house.
I pray, God, you restore
hunger for your presence.
I pray Lord that ancient well wells will
be
dug and reopened again for generations.
May your family, oh God,
house of God walk in fear of the Lord.
And may the old time anointing rest upon
the church again.
We thank you. We bless you.
We worship you.
In Jesus' name.
Amen.
Hallelujah. There's a song that we used
to sing ancient days.
Ancient words
>> Ancient words
>> ever true
>> changing me
>> and changing you.
>> and changing [music]
you.
>> We have come
with open
>> [singing and music]
>> hearts
Oh, let
the ancient words
>> [music and singing]
>> in
ancient words
>> Ancient words
ever [music and singing] true
changing me
and changing [music and singing]
you.
We have come
with open
hearts
Oh, let
>> [music]
>> the ancient words
in
Holy words
>> [music]
>> long preserved
for our
>> [music and singing]
>> walk in this world
They [music and singing] resound
in our hearts
Oh, let [music and singing] the
ancient words
in
>> words of life
>> Words [music]
of life
Words of hope
>> [music]
>> give us
>> [singing]
>> strength.
Let [music] us grow
in this world
wherever [singing]
we go.
>> [music]
>> Ancient words will guide us.
Ancient words
>> [music]
>> Ancient words
ever true
>> [music]
>> changing
and changing [music]
you.
We have come with
with open [music] hearts
all happy
and content
One more time.
>> [music]
>> Ancient words
Ancient words
say ever
>> [music]
>> changing [singing] me and changing
and [music] changing
We have
>> [music]
>> all happy
>> Let's have our heads bowed. Our heads
bowed before God.
You're here this morning as we celebrate
Old School Sunday.
And you know very well you're very far
when it comes to
the real authentic Christianity and
faith.
If you're here and you know very well
that you're
not even close to the kind of faith that
I described here,
please lift up your hand and give us the
privilege to pray for you
on this very special Sunday.
You know very well
your Christianity is not anywhere close
to what I described.
Lift up your hand. I'll pray for you.
I want to see hands going up.
You're here, God bless you.
Anybody else? God bless you. God bless
you. God bless you. God bless you. Quite
a number of them. God bless you. God God
bless you. Come on, put your hands
together for these ones who are lifting
up their hands.
Hallelujah.
Glory to God.
Oh, if if Apostle Paul was to rise up
again today, he would die again. People
have moved so far
from authentic
old ways of God.
God is calling upon us
to go back to his old ways.
Amen.
Amen. I want us to repeat this word.
Dear Lord Jesus,
we thank you because you died for us.
Forgive us our sins.
Wash us with your precious blood.
With our mouth we confess
that you are Lord
and savior. With our heart we believe
we are saved
in Jesus' name. And when you come back
for your church,
remember us
in Jesus' name.
Amen. And amen.
Come on, somebody.
Hallelujah.
If you lifted If If you lifted your hand
up, after the service there will be
pastors here. Pastors will be here.
Please don't go without being prayed
for, and God richly bless you. Let's
have a seat.